よっ。
Invitation x And x Friend
女の子になっちゃったんだ！ 俺は　敵に捕まったって 聞いたけどな。
Anyway, I have to wait for Killua.
カイトは　アリの巣から シュートが救い出してくれて。
Yo, sorry to make you wait.
でも　それは　カイトじゃなくて…。
Do you feel something
constantly watching us?
あいつらに… ひどい目に…　遭わされて！
Yeah, eyes this persistent
can only be a human's. So everyone's noticed.
うっ…。 そいつと　もう一度　会ったら
Well, they can't be too good
if we can sense them from here. Just ignore it.
カイトは　もう死んだって！
We're being watched.
あ　分かった！ いや　分かってねえけど
Killua! Sorry.
まず座れ　なっ？
I don't see any nearby towns.
うんとだな…　まず落ち着くか。
Yeah, but everyone headed
in the same directions.
落ち着こう　俺も　お前も。
They either went this way or that way?
俺が…　わがまま…　言ったから！
Huh? How did you know? Because that's where we're
being watched from.
いや　あの　と　と…　とにかくだ。
But we still don't know
why they're watching us.
とにかく落ち着いて。
True.
ジンが…。
Well, let's go.
あのジンが あたふたしている。
Regardless of who's watching, we should
start by gathering information.
俺が　本当は死ぬべきだったのに！
So, how did it go?
ゴン。 ん？
Your save data. Book.
それは　違う。 あいつが お前を連れて行ったのは
How many cards were inside?
お前なら　できると思ったからだ。
There weren't any cards inside. Huh? For real?
あいつが お前に逃げろと言ったのは
But there was a message from Ging.
その読みが甘かったからだ。
What did he say? To enjoy the game.
お前が何を言おうと 絶対　連れてってねえよ。
But this doesn't really feel like a game.
読みを外したのは あいつの責任だ。 でも！ 分かってる。
Book. What do you think about the rules?
弱っちぃ　お前にも責任はある。 責任は　大いに感じろよ。
I still don't know enough yet.
そして　謝るなら 俺にじゃなく　カイトにだ。
What was that?
お前の話じゃ　生きてんのか 死んでんのか　よく分からんが
Was it Nen?
どっちにしろ行け！
This must be your first
time playing this game.
うん。
I wonder if you're right.
仲間に謝る時は　ルールがある 知ってっか？
Since you're carrying a book,
you must be a player.
えっ？　ううん　何？
Well, sure.
次は　どうするか そいつと約束する。
You can't fool me. I know you're new to this game.
そして　それを絶対　守ることだ。
I can use the Steal card.
うん！ よし　行け！ うん！
Casting Steal.
Select target player.
ジン？ ん？
What is he doing?! Zefespa
Grecoloas
Killua
Gon
もっと話せる？　後で。
Killua-kun and Gon-kun, huh?
うっ　ん… 難しいな…　俺　忙しいし。
How do you know our names? How indeed?
ふざけんなよジン！ てめぇ　それでも父親かよ！
You have zero chance if you don't
know about the spell cards.
血も涙もねえのか　お前には！ 知ってんぞ！ 『グリードアイランド』
View Killua's free slots?
Yes      No
ゴンがクリアしても 会わなかったべ！　内気か！
No cards in Killua's free slots.
Steal card was consumed.
なっ！　くっ！
And that confirms it.
うるせぇな　てめぇら！ 関係ねえだろ！
They're total newbies who just arrived.
ジン　最低！
And they're kids.
お前こそゴンに謝れ！
Adhesion
Complete data of one target
player's restricted slots will
be available at all times.
(Effect lasts until player
leaves the game.)
[SR][ATK]
「これから　ちゃんと父親します」 って約束しろ！
I don't wanna waste this spell on them.
ていうか　偉そうに 父親面すんな！　こら！
Trace should be good enough. Trace on!
どっちだよ！ ふざけんなよ　この野郎！
Attack, Killua!
あ　うっせぇ！　分かったよ！ 待っててやっから　行って来い！
You can't run from spells in this game!
ばかにしてんのか！ てめぇが　ちゃんと連れて行け！
Killua, are you okay?
父親だろうが！ お　よし　分かった！ やってやるよ！
My attack worked!
文句ある奴 まとめて　かかって来い！
What did you just do to me?
全員　敵だな　ＯＫ！ 上等だ　ボケが！　あぁ!?
This kid's dangerous!
み　な　さ　ん！
Take me to Masadora!
そう　まだ　諦めない
Shizuku, Kortopi...
ゴンくん…。 そこで　どうぞ！
Play the game?
えっ？
Yes, would you like to join me?
事情があって 選挙が終わらないと ここから出られないんですよ。
Once we get home,
there's nothing for us to do.
一刻も早く行きたいでしょ？
You really want to clear this game?
でも　これは 正真正銘　最後の投票です。
Actually, clearing it isn't my goal.
投票すれば　すぐ出られます。
Then this relates to Troupe business? More or less.
有効投票だと　会場の皆さんが 認めてくれるでしょう。
Understood. Sure. Killua, how are you holding up?
私　パリストンとレオリオさん
Hmm? I don't feel any different. But I'm still worried.
どちらが 会長にふさわしいと思いますか？
He definitely did something to you.
ちなみに　ネテロ前会長は アリの王を倒し 長期の休暇を取りました。
No point in worrying about it now. Hey, was he using Nen
when he said, "Trace on"?
なぜ　それを あなたが言えるの？
No, it's probably some magic
that only works in the game. Magic? What kind?
ここで劇的に登場した ゴンがレオリオを選べば
Beats me. Well, we'll find out eventually.
みんなが　また 感情と雰囲気に流されて
Yeah. Look, there's a town!
違ぇよ！ いろいろ　あってだな…。
Are those the prizes?
ゴンくん！
Wow, all these are prizes?
直感で　いいんです 心を偽ることだけせず
Looks that way. Oh, Killua... Look.
どちらか選んでください。
"Antokiba Monthly Tournaments Schedule." There's a rock-paper-scissors
tournament this month.
うんと…　じゃあ…
The prize is a Sword of Truth.
パリストンさんで！
Is that an important item? Probably.
えっ！
Look over there.
おや？ レオリオさんは仲間ですよね？
And over there. Should we participate?
いいんですか？ レオリオさんを選ばなくて。
Of course.
うん　だって　レオリオは 医者を目指してるから
Then let's try to win all kinds of prizes.
会長は　やれないよ。
We should also gather information.
あ…。 ですよね！
Welcome! If you can finish this within thirty
minutes, you don't need to pay!
完敗だわ　今度こそ
In addition, you'll also receive
a Galgaida as your prize.
ありがとう　ゴンくん。 では　僕達も 投票に入りましょうか。
Okay, begin!
あっ　悪ぃな　俺も一緒に行くわ。
Hey, chef. Do you know how to use magic?
パリストンに一票よろしく！
What's that?
レオリオ。 分かってるよ。
Who's the most knowledgeable
person in this city? Knowledgeable? What's that?
ジン！ ん？
This guy doesn't know anything.
行って来るね！
He's probably just an in-game character.
おう。 ヘヘヘ…。
Oh, no! You did it!
「おう」じゃねえよ　ばかか！
Here is your prize, Galgaida.
「いってらっしゃい」だろうが！ 常識ねえのか！
"1217.
あ　ジンがキレた！　うわっ
F-185."
誰か！ この育児放棄のクズ　止め…
What does that mean? Is this your first time seeing a card?
無理だって！ 「十二支ん」　笑ってねえで…！ アハハハ…！ ジンって　ある意味　人気者だね。
The left number is the item's card number, and the sequence on the right
ranks how difficult it is to obtain.
あぁ…　そうかな。
There are ten ranks, from SS to H.
おい　ゴン！ ん？ 一つ思い出した。
F would be the third easiest.
カイトに念能力　教えたの俺だ 技もな！
The number next to the rank is the item's
maximum transformation limit.
あいつの 「クレイジースロット」にはな
Oh, which means this item card...
「絶対　死んでたまるか」 って本気で思わねえと
Is nothing but junk.
あいつは　お前の代わりに 犠牲になるなんて
I've never seen him around. That's brutal.
ノミのクソほど 思ってねえからな！
He's one of the players who entered with us.
謝り方　間違えんなよ！
Hey, what happened?
また　ぶっ飛ばされっぞ！
His body suddenly exploded. From the inside.
分かった！　いってきます！
We've only been inside the
game for a few hours, and someone's already dead.
おう！　待ってっぞ！
And this corpse has a very real presence.
こら　この野郎！ あ！
Hard to believe it's a game.
また？
We're risking our lives here.
ジン…
He probably went back to the real world. Game over.
え　皆さん １３代会長のパリストンです。 早速ですが　重大発表です！
I don't know. Don't worry. There's no such spell in this game. Spell?
私　パリストンは 副会長にチードルさんを指名し
As you just said, it's something like magic.
この場で会長を 辞することといたします。
He died from another player's Nen.
あっ　そ。 そこまでは読めんかった。
Nen ? Does that mean the players are
trying to kill each other? Why?
どこまで人をばかにすれば 気が済むの!?
Player hunting? I can explain later.
戻りなさい!!
Anyway, are you interested in teaming up?
僕はね　会長になりたくて 副会長を引き受けたんじゃ　ない。
Huh? If you're interested, follow me. My allies are waiting ahead.
会長の邪魔がしたかっただけ。
What do we do? Sounds suspicious.
ネテロさんはね　僕が 面白い　ちゃちゃを入れると
And we're already off to a bad start.
本当に嬉しそうに困ってた。 もっと会長と
As I recall, on your way here, another player
used an attack spell on you.
遊びたかったなぁ。
Have you been watching us? Yeah.
ハンター試験と 「十ヶ条」の改正は　お早めに。
If you come, I'll explain why. I can also tell you about the
spell that was cast on you. You're being very nice.
チードルさん。
We have no choice.
あなたの協会が 退屈なものだったら…。
This game is difficult,
unpleasant, and frightening.
レオリオ…　キルアは？ ん？　あぁ　いや 分かんねえんだよ
We could be returning players.
ケータイ通じねえし。
Book.
あいつも お前を治す方法　探すため 動き回ってるらしいからなぁ。
This proves that you're beginners.
まぁ　連絡がつけば　すぐ会えるよ。
An experienced player would react
by summoning his own binder.
俺　キルアにも謝らなきゃ。
Because you need spell cards
to defend yourself.
敵と戦ってる時 訳　分かんなくなって
Then the spell cast on Killua... Could only be stopped by another card.
ひどいこと言っちゃったんだ。
Even when you aren't carrying any cards, you should still summon it.
何か　俺こそ悪ぃ。
It's an important bluff. Book.
えっ　何で　レオリオが謝るの？
Hey, how do we obtain spell cards?
いや　お前ら大変な時に すんません。
The easiest method would be to
go to Masadora, City of Magic.
えっ　何　何？　分かんないよ。
Masadora? Return
Warp to a city
of your choice.
(Must be a city
you have visited.)
[LR][NORM] Return on!
いや　ホント もうホントに…。
Take me to Masadora! Killua, we should go with him.
ミルキの報告を受けた時の それが　最初の違和感だった
Everyone else turned me down. Let's get started, then.
結果的に ほっぺにチュで済んだのに
Another player was just killed.
その見返りの「おねだり」が 指の爪では重過ぎる
He arrived with the rest of you. His stomach exploded.
もしも　パソコンの見返りが 指の爪だと仮定すると
It was the Bomber. The Bomber?
今までの経験則に 照らし合わせても
The victims aren't killed by spells.
「お願い」と「おねだり」が 釣り合う この仮定が正しい場合
No spell in this game is capable
of injuring people.
死んだまねや　なでなでは ナニカの「おねだり」ではなく
Which means that you won't be harmed or killed
そして　２択の「お願い」には
by any spell that's been cast on you.
見返りが　いらなかったという 結論が導き出される なぜ 見返りが不要だったのか？
There are forty different spells. The one cast on you was an inspection spell.
推察されるのは　２つ
Either Trace or Adhesion.
２択の結果が　ナニカの能力を 必要としない程度の 易しい「お願い」で　あったから
Trace
Current location of one
target player will be
available at all times.
(Effect lasts until player
leaves the game.)
[SR][ATK] In short, once the enemy uses these on you, Adhesion
Complete data of one target
player's restricted slots will
be available at all times.
(Effect lasts until player
leaves the game.)
[SR][ATK] he will then know everything about you.
または 「お願い」ではなかったから
I get it. That's why...
しかし ここで未解決の問題がある
Some players wait near the starting point
死んだまねや　なでなでが
in order to cast these spells on new players.
ナニカの 「おねだり」でなかった場合 「おねだり」をしたのは アルカであり
As soon as a player obtains a valuable card, they'll show up and steal it.
ナニカでは　なかったことになる
In some cases, they kill their target.
「ナニカは俺のことをキルアと呼ぶ」と キルアは言っており
Like the guy who just died? I won't be that easy to kill.
キルアに　死んだまねを 「おねだり」した時は
No, he was killed by something else.
お兄ちゃんと呼んでいた 従って　お兄ちゃんと呼ぶのは
There is a violent faction hunting players.
アルカと考えるのが妥当である
This was done by one of them... The Bomber.
あの時　「おねだり」をしたのが アルカであるならば
Bomber...
ナニカは目覚めておらず キルアが　その後
In this game, there are three
ways to acquire item cards.
２択の「お願い」をすること自体 不可能なはずであるが
Do you know what they are?
あの時　実際には ナニカがキルアに応答している
Find them yourself. Trade with other players.
この矛盾を解決するヒントが キルアの口調にある
Steal them from other players. Yes, those are the three ways.
２択の時 キルアは「して」ではなく 「しろ」と言っていた
However, the number of players stealing
from others has recently increased.
命令ならば 「お願い」とは無関係に働き 見返りを求めないことは
That's due to the card's difficulty to obtain
and the card transformation limit system.
至極まっとうではないのか
Players who can't obtain cards themselves
…と　考えられるのだが いかがだろうか？
choose to take them from others. If those players resist, they're killed.
率直に言うよ。 ナニカの能力を ゾルディック家のために
When they die, their ring disappears,
and their cards are lost. However, it increases the transformation
limit of that type of card.
安全かつ効率良く使えるのは俺だ。
If you kill a player, you can't take his cards.
今のままじゃ　アルカは 一生　開かずの間の 座敷わらしだよ。
That rule was meant to keep
players from killing one another.
だけど 俺が　お前ごと管理するなら…。
But now, it's backfiring. It's been over ten years since the game's release.
最低限の自由は保障してやれる。
If no one can find a way to beat it, the killing will only continue.
兄貴…。
That's why we're trying to end this mess. We're recruiting allies to clear this game.
アルカは　俺が守る。
3) Steal them. Which method will you use?
キル　分をわきまえろ。 ナニカ　起きろ。
3... I assume you mean to use all three methods, but 3 will be the primary method.
あい。
What, so you'll still use force? No! We won't use violence to reach our goal.
キル　最後だ　ナニカを俺に任せ…。 ナニカ！　イルミを家まで飛ばせ！
Correct. There are certain spells for taking cards, and there are cards that
defend against those spells.
あい。
We'll focus on monopolizing these cards. We're going to use the very
card transformation limit
うわっ！ おお。
that's frustrated the players.
瞬間移動だ　マジで？
This is the only way to clear the game.
何だ　みんなで見てたの？
I have met many players, and they
all reached the same conclusion.
すごいよね　敵なしだよ。
Even if you search for cards,
they'll be taken from you eventually. Because this game is based on
players taking cards from each other.
キルアの命令なら 「おねだり」のリスクなしだ。
We will ensure that we can take
cards from other players, while mitigating our risk of losing cards.
これは キルアを完全な　でくにしても
You're leaving out something important.
お釣りが来る。 [TV]　ツボネ　アマネ。
Upon clearing the game,
how will you split the reward?
[TV]　俺達 ２人だけにしてくれないか？
You were hired by Mr. Battera, right?
[TV]　自発的に行ってくれないと 今みたくナニカに命じなきゃ。
So you knew who we were when you invited us. Yeah. Mr. Battera also hired us to play this game.
キルア　いい子いい子して。
That means the reward will be 50 billion.
ナニカは　俺に褒められたくて やってるだけなんだ。
We'll split it among everyone who helps. Currently, we have fifty-three players.
[TV]　そんなナニカを利用して ホントは　命令なんかしたくない。
It'll take two months to collect
the remaining spell cards, and one month to get the cards we need.
頼むよ。 キルア。
Of course, if you join us, we'll remove any spells cast on you.
キルア。
I'm in.
I don't like the idea of splitting the 50 billion.
キルア。 ナニカ。
But I like the three month schedule
for clearing the game.
キルア　いい子いい子して。 もう　お前は　出て来ちゃダメだ。
What about you? I have a question. If I obtain an SS rank card on
my own, what's my cut? Naturally, you'd receive 500 million
for a card of that rank.
キルア　好き。 あっ。
Okay, I'm in. What about you two? Killua, sorry.
ダメなんだ　ナニカ。
I'm out.
キルア好き。
I'm playing this game on my own.
キルア好き。 ダメだ！　もう二度と出て来るな！ 分かったな！
You heard the leader. I have to pass. Hey, Gon! Wait up...
あい。
We'll need you to first exit the game, so the spells placed on you can be removed.
これで　アルカは自由になれる
Once you're back in the game,
wait by the starting point. We'll come get you. If you have any cards in your free slots, give them to me now.
ごめん！　ごめんな　ナニカ！ ごめん！
Why? When you leave the game, the cards in your free slots disappear.
ん？
I believe your data automatically
saves when cards are put in or removed from restricted slots.
アルカ？
Yes, but your data disappears
お兄ちゃん？
If you don't return before then,
we'll assume that you gave up. Got it?
ああ　お兄ちゃ…。 あっ。
Don't worry, we're being joined by an ally.
お兄ちゃんが泣かしたの？ ナニカを？
We don't know if anyone's watching.
えっ？　あっ　いや…　その…。
Let's get started. Leave
Send one
target player
off the island.
[SR][NORM] I'll be using the Leave card.
今も　うずくまって泣いているよ！ ナニカに謝って！
Hey, Gon...
うん　でも…。 謝るの！
Will you explain what that was about?
アルカに優しいお兄ちゃんは ナニカにも優しくなきゃダメ！
Sorry, Killua. I couldn't take it anymore.
あっ…。
I still don't get why you're apologizing. But this means you'll be stuck
with that spell for a while.
アルカを守ってくれるなら
Oh, that's why. It's not a big deal.
ナニカも守らなきゃダメ!!
But you're playing this game
あっ…。
to help me find my dad...
ナニカをいじめる お兄ちゃんなんか　大嫌い!!
You're wrong. I'm playing this game because...
アルカ　ありがとうな。
Because they had nothing
but bad things to say about the game Ging made, like how
it's based on killing and stealing.
俺　まだ　イル兄に 縛られてたらしいや。
I want to do what Ging said,
and enjoy the game.
もう　これでホントに大丈夫。
When I first started, I knew it wouldn't be easy.
ナニカを　呼んでもいいか？ うん。
That was because I thought all the
players enjoyed playing the game.
ナニカ　ごめんな。
Really? I think it makes sense.
俺が間違ってた　ごめん。
Killua, you really mean that? That's why this game is meant for Hunters.
俺　ずっとイル兄が怖くて 逆らえなくて
But... Killing is wrong. I agree with you on that part.
言いなりになってて それが　すごい嫌で…。 俺だけじゃなく 今度は　ナニカに無理やり嫌なこと 命令されたらって考えたら
But what if two players have a fair
fight with predetermined rules, and the winner gets to take a card? Th-That's acceptable.
すごく怖くなって。
See? When that guy cast a spell on me
アルカのためにって 自分に嘘をついて
and when those guys carry out their plan, they're just following the game's rules.
お前に　ひどいこと言っちゃった。
Yeah.
本当に　ごめん！
Though it does still feel lame. Well, forget about them.
ナニカ　お前は俺が守る！
Let's enjoy this game.
ずっと一緒だ！
Killua... Hmm?
他の奴の「お願い」なんか もう聞くな！
Thanks.
俺が　いつでも　お前を いい子いい子してやる！
I'm glad you came with me. No...
だから　もう一度 出て来てくれるか？
I'm glad I got to know you! Cut it out, stupid.
あい。
I'm the one who's glad
ナニカ。 こんな… ダメなお兄ちゃんでも…
Such a beautiful thing, the friendship
and innocence of two young boys.
許してくれるか？ あい。
I feel like messing with them.
キルア… 好き。
But who is the girl watching them?